Ariel Lima Andrade

Salvador, BA, Brazil +55 (71) 99142-3654 (https://sudoariel.github.io

egthinspace =
egtlima.ariel97@gmail.com (7)

https://github.com/sudoariel

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ariellima/

ABOUT ME

I love programming and challenges. My professors and employers have commended me for my high level of responsibility, teamwork, proactivity, problem solving skills and my ability to master new skills quickly. I am extremely motivated in overcoming challenges, learning new concepts and working well as a part of a team where we are able to share experiences and optimize results.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FEB 2022 - AUG 202I (FT)

Ford Motor Company Android Automotive OS Developer

Android Operating System modification and extension for custom vehicle hardware. Java/Kotlin application development for Android Automotive. Embedded Android/Linux systems.

JULY 2020 - JULY 2021 (FT)

Ford Motor Company Software Developer Analyst

Desktop, mobile and automotive embedded systems development. Vehicle modules prototypes development. Android Automotive embedded (AOSP). Programming languages: C/C++/C#/Java/Python.

JUNE 2019 - JULY 2020 (PT)

Ford Motor Company Software Developer Intern

Computer Engineering Intern in Software Team at Ford South America. Embedded and desktop software development.

OCT 2018 - DEC 2018 (PT)

SENAI BAHIA Technical Advisor

Technical training specialized in PLC and HMI programming and FESTO MPS assembly and commissioning for Mechatronics competitors of the WorldSkills Competition 2019 in Kazan, Russia. Designing FESTO MPS layouts and programming tasks.

JUNE 2016 – JUNE 2017 (PT)

SENAI CIMATEC - Industrial Automation Technical trainee

Training for the WorldSkills Selective Abu Dhabi 2017 as a competitor: PLC and HMI programming (Siemens), assembly, maintenance and commissioning in integrated manufacturing systems (FESTO). Maintenance and inspection in laboratories of Industrial Robotics, Digital Systems and Control and Mechatronics. Assistance in a research and innovation project: DECA (crockery brazilian factory) crockery automation project. Experience in motion control, Rexroth PLC and HMI programming.

EDUCATION

2017 - CURRENT **B.E.** Computer Engineering

> Electrical & Computer Engineer Federal University of Bahia (UFBA)

A.S. Electrotechnology 2014 – 2016

> Technical School SENAI Cimatec

AWARDS

Cost Award and Recognition 202I

Ford Motor Company

VCSE Leadership Awards 2020

Ford Motor Company

VCSE People's Choice Awards 2020

Ford Motor Company

VCSE Excellence Awards 2019

Ford Motor Company

Robustness Award 2017

Brazilian Robotics Olympiad (OBR)

2016 Runner-up in Mechatronics

Selective WorldSkills Abu Dhabi 2017

COMPUTER SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Javascript BEGINNER INTERMEDIATE C, C++, Python, Kotlin

ADVANCED C#, Java

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Advanced level ENGLISH SPANISH Intermediate level PORTUGUESE Native speaker

SKILLS

Problem-solving

Problems are inevitable in daily work routine. I feel motivated when new challenges arise, which opens space for my creativity and innovativeness.

Teamwork

I've worked as a team member on several engineering projects where we were successful and awarded for bringing innovative solutions.

Willingness to learn

I am an active learner interested in learning new concepts and technologies and also expanding the knowledge I have on topics that I am familiar with.